大家好 我叫Jasmin Moghbeli
Hi, I'm Jasmin Moghbeli.
我是NASA的宇航员 这里是“#AskNASA”栏目
I'm a NASA astronaut and this is #AskNASA.
NASA打算在3月2日到3月31日期间招募更多宇航员
NASA will be opening its applications for more astronauts on March 2nd through March 31st.
我们收到了很多相关的问题
So, we've got a bunch of questions related to that.
这个在线评估是关于什么的？
What is this online assessment about?
它会测试你的天赋与技能水平
It's testing things like your aptitude and skills
从而保证你在整个流程早期你就有成为NASA宇航员所需要的的资质
to make sure earlier in the process that you have what it takes to be a NASA astronaut.
好 下一个问题
Okay, let's move on to our next question.
哪些学位不算数？
What degrees don't count?
我想从正面来回答 哪些学位是符合要求的
So I like to be positive and start with what degrees do count.
你需要获得研究生的学位
So, you do need a master's degree.
谢谢！
Thanks!
而且需要是STEM学科的研究生学位 即科学、技术、工程或者数学
You need a master's degree in a STEM field so Science, Technology, Engineering or Mathematics.
有些学位是不行的 比如护理学 心理学
There are certain degrees in there that don't count such as nursing, psychology,
运动生理学或社会科学
exercise physiology or social sciences,
具体细节请前往nasa.gov/astronauts
but for details on that you can go to nasa.gov/astronauts.
你面试时被问到的最奇怪的问题是什么？
What was the weirdest question you got during your interview?
Valsalva动作：捏住鼻子用力呼气
我面试时一个耳科医生问我能否做一个Valsalva动作
So, when I went to see the ear doctor in the interview, and he asked if I could do a Valsalva Maneuver.
你们坐飞机的时候可能也做过这个动作
You may be familiar with that from flying in commercial aircraft.
反正我做完之后 他说我的Valsalva动作非常标准
Anyway, afterwords he told me I did textbook Valsalva.
完美
Shoo in.
下一个问题
Next question.
成为阿尔忒弥斯计划的宇航员之一 你最激动的是什么？
What are you most excited about for being a part of the Artemis generation?
哇！
Wow!
这可有的聊了
I could go on about that one for a while.
首先 我们到现在还没去过别的星球
First off, we haven't stepped on another planetary body in my lifetime.
所以如果我认识的某个人踏上了月球 我会非常激动
So, it will be super exciting to see someone I know stepping on the surface of the Moon.
同时 这也使我们为未来的任务做进一步的准备
But also, how that sets us up for future missions
让我们在太阳系中走得更远 比如去火星
to go farther than we have ever gone in our solar system before, on to Mars.
@shifte_mir：你要训练多少小时？
我们现在一直在训练
So, we're constantly working on training.
我们前两年纯粹都是训练
Our first two years were purely training.
明天我要去中性浮力实验室练习太空行走
Tomorrow I'm getting in the neutral buoyancy lab to practice a spacewalk.
周五我还要上T-38飞机 所以这是个日复一日的持续的过程
Friday I'm getting in a T-38, so it's a continuous process every day.
好 我们看下一个问题
Here, let's move on to our next question.
为何宇航员要通过体检？
Why do astronauts need to pass a physical?
实际上宇航员在训练的时候会涉及到很多身体有关的内容
So, there are actually lots of physical aspects to our astronaut training
从我过去两年持续的训练中我就能亲身感受到这一点
and I can tell you that from the last two years I've constantly been working out.
而你将来要进行太空行走
But you need to be able to one, do the spacewalks.
你还要能坐火箭发射到太空 还要能开喷气机
You also need to be able to launch to space, fly in jets,
所以NASA希望我们每个人都能有最好的身体条件
so we need to make sure everyone is in their best physical condition.
@rose._.valade：太空行走训练时你第一反应是怎样的？
我第一次穿上舱外宇航服的时候 我发现这比我想得要难得多
Well the first time I got in the suit, it was a lot harder than I thought it was going to be.
你要在整件宇航服内工作 它就是你的小型飞船 真的非常累
You're working within this whole spacesuit, it's really your own spacecraft and it's really tiring.
太空“行走”用的是手 而不是脚
You walk with your hands, not your feet.
你做的每件事都会让你发现自己比平常要大上一圈
Everything you do, you're much bigger than you expect to be
所以你要确保不要碰到别的东西
so you have to make sure you're not running into things.
我第一想法就是感觉 太爽了 但也太难了
My first thought was, this is awesome, but this it's also really hard.
@grajohnt: 我有个朋友问我 能不能写信 别给我发拒绝我的电子邮件？
告诉你的“朋友” 我们NASA是很爱护地球的 我们不想浪费纸张
Well, tell your "friend" that at NASA we really like the planet Earth and we don't wanna waste all that paper.
我们上次收到了8000份申请 所以我们可能还是用电子邮件
We had over eighteen thousand applications last time so, we'll probably stick with emails.
@marissasayr：这份工作带给你最好的经历是什么？
我目前为止最好的经历就是遇见了在这里工作的其他人
My best experience, by far, has been meeting the other people that work here.
不止是其他宇航员 还有在任务中心工作的工程师
Not just the other astronauts, but the engineers, those that work in Mission Control,
每天为我们提供支持的所有人
all the support personnel that help us every day.
比如在中性浮力实验室的潜水员们
The divers at the Neutral Buoyancy Lab.
在约翰逊太空中心和所有其他NASA中心 每天都有很多人为我们提供支持
We've got so many people here at Johnson Space Center and all the other NASA centers supporting us every day.
嗯 这就是我们所有的问题
All right, that's all our questions.
完美！
Perfect!
你有什么问题想问NASA吗？
Do you have a question for NASA?
欢迎在推特上加上“#AskNASA ”标签将您的问题发送给我们的专家
Send your questions to our experts on Twitter using #AskNASA.